Lara S. da Luz UI Designer

Able to work in EU
Open to relocate
Open to remote roles

+351 934714040

• Coimbra, Portugal

Hard Skills

- UI Design
- UX Design
- Wireframes
- Prototypes
- Personas
- User test
- Iconography
- Mock-ups
- Brand Design
- User flows
- Illustrations

Soft Skills

- Communication
- Creative thinking
- Team work
- Self motivated
- Attention to details
- Organized

Tools

- Figma
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe InDesign
- HTML/CSS
- Adobe Premiere Pro
- Adobe After Effects
- Procreate

Education

Oct 2023 - July 2024

UI Design Program

CareerFoundry

Sep 2020 - Sep 2023

Graduation in Graphic Design & Multimedia

University of Coimbra

About Me

As a UI Designer with a background in illustration and graphic design, I strive for the perfect balance of aesthetics and usability. My experience enhances my work in iconography, research, and wireframing. I'm able to add value to your ideas and have a empathetic view on users. Whether working alone or with a team, I am flexible and capable of delivering superior design work.



UI/UX Projects

GoCamino

UI/UX Design - Project View

Feb 2024 - April 2024 CareerFoundry

A location-based website that helps future pilgrims plan and not get lost in their path with maps and information about all their possibilities.

- Competitive Analysis and Interviews to find the main difficulties around the topic
- Wireframing and Usability Testing to start the design and find the best solutions
- Personas and User Flow to define the main design goals

Down to earth

UI Design - <u>Project View</u>

June 2024 - July 2024

CareerFoundry

A finance management app that provides essential tools to track past expenses, plan future expenses, and manage investments and savings for financial peace.

- Based in the **User Stories** a personal research on finance applications, created a User Flow to guide my design choices
- User testing with the wireframes to analyze main mistakes
- Brand design is minimalistic and delicate, to bring peace and clearness to the user's mind
- Mockups to showcase the final design

The Tome

UI/UX Design - Project View

May 2024 - June 2024

CareerFoundry

Most Dungeons & Dragons (D&D) players struggle with creating a character from scratch. The Tome app assists users in creating and managing characters, and is compatible with both iOS and Android platforms.

- Created 3 main usabilities for the app based on my research
- Studied main differences between IOs and Android design rules
- Iconography I designed all the icons of the app
- Prototyped all the process

Experience

Website for data management

UI Design - Project View

June 2023 - July 2023 Rilix Company

The company needed a website to manage better their orders and communication between the team, so everyone knows the situation and the person responsible for each order.

• Worked with the company's programming team

ADHD Stories for Children

Illustration - Project View

Oct 2023 - Dec 2023

- Simple story with a complex message that I worked to communicate well
- Planning and team work